<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2017-08-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>resume</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2017/08/01/resume/"/>
    <id>/2017/08/01/resume/</id>
    <published>2017-08-01T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2017-08-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;h2 id='skills'&gt;Skills&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id='languages'&gt;Languages&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Ruby, Python, Javascript, Java, C, Clojure, SQL, HTML&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h4 id='frameworks'&gt;Frameworks&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Ruby on Rails, Flask, AngularJs, EmberJs, jQuery, Bootstrap&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h4 id='tools'&gt;Tools&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Linux, Ansible, Vagrant, Docker, Git, Postgresql, Mysql, nginx, AWS&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h4 id='methodologies'&gt;Methodologies&lt;/h4&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2 id='skills'&gt;Skills&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id='languages'&gt;Languages&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Ruby, Python, Javascript, Java, C, Clojure, SQL, HTML&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h4 id='frameworks'&gt;Frameworks&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Ruby on Rails, Flask, AngularJs, EmberJs, jQuery, Bootstrap&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h4 id='tools'&gt;Tools&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Linux, Ansible, Vagrant, Docker, Git, Postgresql, Mysql, nginx, AWS&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h4 id='methodologies'&gt;Methodologies&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Agile, TDD, OOP, responsive design, OWASP security practices.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h4 id='project_management'&gt;Project management&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Full lifecycle project development; requirements gathering, estimation, sprint planning, release and maintenance.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id='experience'&gt;Experience&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id='consultant'&gt;Consultant&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dec 2015 - Present&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://factu.ly/'&gt;factu.ly&lt;/a&gt; is an MVP that aims to address the problem of fake news by allowing users to upload and annotate articles, and rate their accuracy and bias.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Created a web application that extracts article headlines and content from urls, and allows selected text to be annotated and rated.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Created a chrome extension that indicates scores and comments for articles currently being viewed, if they exist in the backend.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Created re-usable Ansible automation scripts that handle server provisioning and deployment for ruby on rails applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.freshsqueezedideas.com/'&gt;freshsqueezedideas.com&lt;/a&gt; is an evidenced-based marketing and design agency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Created a web application for building and administering multi-stage surveys. Subsequent stages are composed of user input comparing various brands and products.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://thecouncil.on.ca'&gt;thecouncil.on.ca&lt;/a&gt; is the bargaining agent for the 24 Ontario colleges in negotiating collective agreements with unionized staff. Their technology stack consists of a Rails 3 CMS with a separate layer for managing arbitrations, and creating multi-step and multi-party scheduling workflows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed numerous bugs around the logic dealing with scheduling time-slots.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Migrated all Rails infrastructure from Linode to Digital Ocean.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Created a re-usable development virtual machine for ruby on rails applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://bitmaker.co'&gt;bitmaker.co&lt;/a&gt; is a well established code academy that equips students with in-demand technical skills and facilitates connections to local companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Created and hosted their brochure site based on design mockups and static html.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Add CMS functionality to enable news and events posting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://concertsherpa.ca'&gt;concertsherpa.ca&lt;/a&gt; is a music event aggregator and news service for &lt;a href='http://exclaim.ca'&gt;exclaim.ca&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Addressed various hosting issues and migrated the ruby on rails 3 application to Heroku, while also fixing problems with the content stream sources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://crowdmark.com/'&gt;crowdmark.com&lt;/a&gt; is an online grading, annotation and analytics platform for scanned test papers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implemented annotation functionality in EmberJs, allowing for manipulation of selected text.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id='software_developer'&gt;Software developer&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mar 2013 - Dec 2015&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://shifthealth.ca'&gt;shifthealth.ca&lt;/a&gt; provides a platform for administering surveys in clinics and hospitals, and collecting patient reported data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Created an offline-capable javascript single-page survey app for use on iOS and android mobile devices.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Expanded the backing Ruby on Rails infrastructure to support reporting, i18n, encrypted backups and deployment automation.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Improved stability of the codebase by implementing continuous integration, monitoring, end to end and integration testing, a strict git branching model, code reviews and sprint planning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id='software_developer'&gt;Software developer&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apr 2011 - Dec 2012&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.thinkresearch.com/ca/'&gt;thinkresearch.com&lt;/a&gt; is a suite of tools and services for managing digital versions of hospital order sets. Primarily responsible for feature development, testing and maintenance of a medical document parser. The tool also serves as a CMS, also allowing for modification and versioning of order-set document content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developed various features and improvements for a pdf document parsing engine.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Improved stability, performance and code coverage of the system through the addition of a test suite.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Participated in and led biweekly sprint feature planning, ticket breakdown and design discussions.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Ensured cross-browser and IE7+ backwards compatibility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id='software_developer'&gt;Software developer&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mar 2010 - Apr 2011&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://fieldid.com/'&gt;fieldid.com&lt;/a&gt; is an asset management and inspection scheduling system for the construction and manufacturing industries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identified, traced and fixed bugs for both front- and back-ends; performed automatic and manual regression testing on both the web and windows mobile applications at the end of each development cycle.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Designed and developed front-end functionality with a heavy emphasis on UI/UX for non-technical users.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Maintained an extensive Selenium integration test suite.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id='net_intern'&gt;.NET Intern&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jun 2006 - Sep 2006&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://konverge.com/'&gt;konverge.com&lt;/a&gt; is a Microsoft application consultancy with clients such as Bosch and KPMG.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designed and wrote C# unit tests for an automotive component price quote system commissioned by Bosch.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Identified, traced and remedied anomalies, bugs, and mathematical errors in the pricing calculation modules.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id='education'&gt;Education&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;University of Toronto, St. George, Toronto&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hons. B.Sc, Computer Science: Software Engineering.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>emacs vs vim</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2017/05/08/emacs-vim/"/>
    <id>/2017/05/08/emacs-vim/</id>
    <published>2017-05-08T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2017-05-08T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;After spending the better part of last year using emacs (specifically the spacemacs distribution) before switching to neovim I can safely conclude I&amp;#8217;ve shaved enough yaks to last me a lifetime. I&amp;#8217;m switching back to Atom because configuring editors is a waste of time that could be better spent actually building things. I could be meticulously&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After spending the better part of last year using emacs (specifically the spacemacs distribution) before switching to neovim I can safely conclude I&amp;#8217;ve shaved enough yaks to last me a lifetime. I&amp;#8217;m switching back to Atom because configuring editors is a waste of time that could be better spent actually building things. I could be meticulously installing and configuring packages for crucial features like fuzzy project search, OR I could just use a modern editor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily most of the emacs navigation keybindings work in atom. God bless.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Rails and default_scope</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2017/02/28/default-scope/"/>
    <id>/2017/02/28/default-scope/</id>
    <published>2017-02-28T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2017-02-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It should be common knowledge by now NOT to use default_scope unless you know what you&amp;#8217;re doing. I &lt;em&gt;thought&lt;/em&gt; I knew what I was doing but was wrong, which is often the case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine having a model with a boolean :finished attribute. And in your schema for this table default: false.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It should be common knowledge by now NOT to use default_scope unless you know what you&amp;#8217;re doing. I &lt;em&gt;thought&lt;/em&gt; I knew what I was doing but was wrong, which is often the case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine having a model with a boolean :finished attribute. And in your schema for this table default: false. You want to only ever retrieve instances that are marked finished, so you write&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;default_scope {where(finished: true)}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great, but guess what? New instances of this model will have their :finished default to true, contrary to the schema definition. Crazy right? Don&amp;#8217;t use default_scope.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Public commitments</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2016/09/07/commitments/"/>
    <id>/2016/09/07/commitments/</id>
    <published>2016-09-07T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-09-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Another one of those corny lifehacks I&amp;#8217;m fond of is public commitments. I guess it&amp;#8217;s semi-common knowledge that announcing your intentions publicly or better yet, to friends, prompts action. I&amp;#8217;ve also noticed it&amp;#8217;s useful for folks suffering from depression and anxiety, insofar that making commitments to see friends or attend&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Another one of those corny lifehacks I&amp;#8217;m fond of is public commitments. I guess it&amp;#8217;s semi-common knowledge that announcing your intentions publicly or better yet, to friends, prompts action. I&amp;#8217;ve also noticed it&amp;#8217;s useful for folks suffering from depression and anxiety, insofar that making commitments to see friends or attend events gets you out of the house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that in mind, I&amp;#8217;m announcing my intention to pivot my career towards automation and ops, plug some holes in my game and learn a few new tricks. Luckily, like Arnold, my cpu is a neural net processor&amp;#8230;a learning computah.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Linux&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite using the terminal and interacting with servers almost daily, my knowledge is broad but shallow. I&amp;#8217;m getting a lot of mileage out of &lt;a href='http://unixmages.com/ufbm.pdf'&gt;Unix for Mages&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href='https://serversforhackers.com/'&gt;Servers for hackers&lt;/a&gt; as refreshers for things I don&amp;#8217;t normally do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Python&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tool of choice for automation scripting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ansible+Vagrant or Docker&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not sure which side to take yet, but for the time-being Ansible suits my needs nicely. Shout-out to the mad genius &lt;a href='https://twitter.com/sheysewani'&gt;Shey&lt;/a&gt; over at &lt;a href='https://polymorphic.ca'&gt;polymorphic.ca&lt;/a&gt; for putting me on this path and sharing some of his hard-won knowledge and high quality scripts.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>gittip</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2016/08/22/gittip/"/>
    <id>/2016/08/22/gittip/</id>
    <published>2016-08-22T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-08-22T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;To remove a specific commit, aka reverse cherry-pick:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git rebase -p --onto SHA^ SHA&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;To remove a specific commit, aka reverse cherry-pick:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git rebase -p --onto SHA^ SHA&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>I've solved procrastination</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2016/07/11/hello-again/"/>
    <id>/2016/07/11/hello-again/</id>
    <published>2016-07-11T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-07-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s right, after 3.5 years of inactivity this blog lives again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Such a long delay&amp;#8230;but overcoming procrastination is Hard. To that end, some tricks that have helped me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do the smallest possible task&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start small and change 1 line of code. Wash 1 dish. Think about 1 thing. Almost always this snowballs into other tasks.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s right, after 3.5 years of inactivity this blog lives again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Such a long delay&amp;#8230;but overcoming procrastination is Hard. To that end, some tricks that have helped me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do the smallest possible task&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start small and change 1 line of code. Wash 1 dish. Think about 1 thing. Almost always this snowballs into other tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Focus&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously, right? But getting there is only half the trouble. Getting into flow is tricky and distractions are the mindkiller. F5&amp;#8217;ing hackernews won&amp;#8217;t get anything finished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Visualize completing the task&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aaah the sweetest feeling. Completing something, no matter how small, is a morale boost. Small increments lead to big changes.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
