<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2018-12-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>End of 2018</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2018/12/12/end-of-year/"/>
    <id>/2018/12/12/end-of-year/</id>
    <published>2018-12-12T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2018-12-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It turns out habitual blogging is difficult, but persistence is it&amp;#8217;s own reward. Time to reflect on 2018 and then think about where to steer the ship, or pull the elephant if you prefer animal metaphors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id='career_stuff'&gt;Career stuff&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I opted to continue client work after getting the opportunity to build/manage the cloud infrastructure and development processes for a couple of companies. It leveled up large chunks of my knowledge, and allowed me to learn tons about DNS, network configuration, security, secrets management and a myriad of other sysadmin related things. In addition to the usual trouble-shoot this and fix that of regular software development.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It turns out habitual blogging is difficult, but persistence is it&amp;#8217;s own reward. Time to reflect on 2018 and then think about where to steer the ship, or pull the elephant if you prefer animal metaphors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id='career_stuff'&gt;Career stuff&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I opted to continue client work after getting the opportunity to build/manage the cloud infrastructure and development processes for a couple of companies. It leveled up large chunks of my knowledge, and allowed me to learn tons about DNS, network configuration, security, secrets management and a myriad of other sysadmin related things. In addition to the usual trouble-shoot this and fix that of regular software development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My previous career goal set around this time last year was to gain dev-ops and sysadmin experience in order to transition into more security oriented work and projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='back_to_security_study'&gt;Back to security study&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://github.com/gradiuscypher/infosec_getting_started'&gt;How me, a programmer, learn security??&lt;/a&gt; Turns out I&amp;#8217;m not the only one to have this idea. Here&amp;#8217;s another &lt;a href='https://tisiphone.net/2015/10/12/starting-an-infosec-career-the-megamix-chapters-1-3/'&gt;classic&lt;/a&gt;. To that end, I&amp;#8217;ve resumed self-study and practice according to a vague curriculum I&amp;#8217;m putting together. More on that in another blog post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id='personal_stuff'&gt;Personal stuff&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year I managed to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nurture closer relationships with people I care about, respect and admire. Particularly &lt;a href='https://laurachuang.net'&gt;a person I care deeply about.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Move to Berlin. Living elsewhere is incredibly refreshing.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Live minimalist. I reconsidered what stuff I actually need. But also, which luxuries brings me joy? A good soundsystem + music, easy access to a gym, and a nice kitchen for example. Regardless of where in the world I am, if there is a place to lift heavy things nearby that&amp;#8217;s already a huge quality of life increase.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Work out a lot, and start Muay Thai and BJJ training.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Re-learn german. Going forward hoffentlich mehr auf Deutsch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Resume</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2018/11/08/resume/"/>
    <id>/2018/11/08/resume/</id>
    <published>2018-11-08T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2018-11-08T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;h1 id='roumen_pavlov'&gt;Roumen Pavlov&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='mailto:roumen@rpavlov.com'&gt;roumen@rpavlov.com&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8226; +359 892 203 147 &amp;#8226; Berlin, Germany&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technical skills&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Languages&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frameworks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tools&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody /&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id='roumen_pavlov'&gt;Roumen Pavlov&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='mailto:roumen@rpavlov.com'&gt;roumen@rpavlov.com&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8226; +359 892 203 147 &amp;#8226; Berlin, Germany&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technical skills&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Languages&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frameworks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tools&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style='text-align: center;'&gt;Strongest&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style='text-align: center;'&gt;Ruby&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style='text-align: center;'&gt;Ruby on Rails&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style='text-align: center;'&gt;Linux&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style='text-align: center;' /&gt;&lt;td style='text-align: center;'&gt;Python&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style='text-align: center;'&gt;Flask, Django&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style='text-align: center;'&gt;AWS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style='text-align: center;' /&gt;&lt;td style='text-align: center;'&gt;SQL&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style='text-align: center;'&gt;AngularJS&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style='text-align: center;'&gt;Mysql, Postgresql&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style='text-align: center;'&gt;&amp;#8595;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style='text-align: center;'&gt;HTML, CSS&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style='text-align: center;'&gt;jQuery&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style='text-align: center;'&gt;Docker, Vagrant&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style='text-align: center;' /&gt;&lt;td style='text-align: center;'&gt;Javascript&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style='text-align: center;'&gt;Bootstrap&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style='text-align: center;'&gt;Ansible&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style='text-align: center;' /&gt;&lt;td style='text-align: center;'&gt;Java&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style='text-align: center;' /&gt;&lt;td style='text-align: center;'&gt;nginx&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style='text-align: center;' /&gt;&lt;td style='text-align: center;'&gt;Clojure&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style='text-align: center;' /&gt;&lt;td style='text-align: center;'&gt;RabbitMQ, Celery&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style='text-align: center;'&gt;Weakest&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style='text-align: center;' /&gt;&lt;td style='text-align: center;' /&gt;&lt;td style='text-align: center;'&gt;Elasticsearch&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id='experience'&gt;Experience&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Consultant&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;#8226; Dec 2015 - Present&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://tealvalley.com/'&gt;https://tealvalley.com&lt;/a&gt; is a web platform for clinics and their patients a to prepare and fulfill prescriptions for narcotics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setup and managed AWS infrastructure for API and web applications across multiple production and development environments.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Setup integrations for a multitude of 3rd party services such as CircleCI, Papertrail, Rollbar in addition to others used by the core applications such as Elasticsearch and Redis.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Managed DNS, SSL, and Cloudflare configurations.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Managed non core-business services such as Github, Slack and GSuite.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Implemented secrets management for credentials to projects and 3rd party services.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Containerized the API with Docker and setup a hosting &amp;amp; deployment workflow in Amazon ECS.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Implemented and maintained features of a Rails API, such as a new public registration workflow.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Implemented and maintained features of a Rails frontend, such as bringing all markup in line with the AODA accessibility standards.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Created and maintained documentation describing the key pieces of the projects, how they interact and their supporting infrastructure such as VPC layout, security groups, load-balancers and IAM roles.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Ran sprints and prioritized tasks for other developers.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Worked closely with non-technical team-members to answer questions and discuss trade-offs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://qoints.com/'&gt;https://qoints.com&lt;/a&gt; is a digital marketing benchmarking platform and social media influencer analysis tool. It performs personality analysis using IBM Watson and tensorflow, with input from a user&amp;#8217;s Twitter content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Management of all AWS infrastructure and technical assets, as well as ownership of multiple Django and ReactJs codebases.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Implemented various features for the Django API server and React client application, such as geographic filtering for user profiles.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Heavily modified the existing payment system and Stripe API integrations in order to add a free-tier.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Mentored junior developers.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Worked closely with non-technical team-members to answer questions and discuss trade-offs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://thecouncil.on.ca'&gt;https://thecouncil.on.ca&lt;/a&gt; is the bargaining agent for the 24 Ontario colleges in negotiating collective agreements with unionized staff. Their technology stack consists of a Rails 3 CMS with a separate layer for managing arbitrations, and creating multi-step and multi-party scheduling workflows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed numerous bugs around the logic dealing with scheduling time-slots.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Migrated all Rails infrastructure from Linode to Digital Ocean.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Created a re-usable development virtual machine for ruby on rails applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.freshsqueezedideas.com/'&gt;https://freshsqueezedideas.com&lt;/a&gt; is an evidenced-based marketing and design agency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Full lifecycle project development; requirements gathering, estimation, sprint planning, release and maintenance.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Created a web application for building and administering multi-stage surveys. Subsequent stages are composed of user input comparing various brands and products.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://bitmaker.co'&gt;https://bitmaker.co&lt;/a&gt; is a well established code academy that equips students with in-demand technical skills and facilitates connections to local companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Created and hosted their brochure site based on design mockups and static html.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Add CMS functionality to enable news and events posting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://factu.ly/'&gt;https://factu.ly&lt;/a&gt; is an MVP that aims to address the problem of fake news by allowing users to upload and annotate articles, and rate their accuracy and bias.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Created a web application that extracts article headlines and content from urls, and allows selected text to be annotated and rated.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Created a chrome extension that indicates scores and comments for articles currently being viewed, if they exist in the backend.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Created re-usable Ansible automation scripts that handle server provisioning and deployment for ruby on rails applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://concertsherpa.ca'&gt;https://concertsherpa.ca&lt;/a&gt; is a music event aggregator and news service for &lt;a href='http://exclaim.ca'&gt;exclaim.ca&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Addressed various hosting issues and migrated the ruby on rails 3 application to Heroku, while also fixing problems with the content stream sources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Software developer&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;#8226; Mar 2013 - Dec 2015&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://shifthealth.ca'&gt;https://shifthealth.ca&lt;/a&gt; provides a platform for administering surveys in clinics and hospitals, and collecting patient reported data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Created an offline-capable javascript single-page survey app for use on iOS and android mobile devices.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Expanded the backing Ruby on Rails infrastructure to support reporting, i18n, encrypted backups and deployment automation.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Improved stability of the codebase by implementing continuous integration, monitoring, end to end and integration testing, a strict git branching model, code reviews and sprint planning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Software developer&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;#8226; Apr 2011 - Dec 2012&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.thinkresearch.com/ca/'&gt;https://thinkresearch.com&lt;/a&gt; is a suite of tools and services for managing digital versions of hospital order sets. Primarily responsible for feature development, testing and maintenance of a medical document parser. The tool also serves as a CMS, also allowing for modification and versioning of order-set document content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developed various features and improvements for a pdf document parsing engine.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Improved stability, performance and code coverage of the system through the addition of a test suite.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Participated in and led biweekly sprint feature planning, ticket breakdown and design discussions.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Ensured cross-browser and IE7| backwards compatibility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Software developer&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;#8226; Mar 2010 - Apr 2011&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://fieldid.com/'&gt;https://fieldid.com&lt;/a&gt; is an asset management and inspection scheduling system for the construction and manufacturing industries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identified, traced and fixed bugs for both front- and back-ends; performed automatic and manual regression testing on both the web and windows mobile applications at the end of each development cycle.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Designed and developed front-end functionality with a heavy emphasis on UI/UX for non-technical users.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Maintained an extensive Selenium integration test suite.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='education'&gt;Education&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;University of Toronto, St. George, Toronto&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hons. B.Sc, Computer Science: Software Engineering.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Book reviews</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2017/11/12/nonviolent-communication/"/>
    <id>/2017/11/12/nonviolent-communication/</id>
    <published>2017-11-12T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2017-11-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been meaning to get into the process of taking notes while reading books. Lets start with Nonviolent Communication by Marshall Rosenberg.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id='surface_thoughts'&gt;Surface thoughts&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All communication must be grounded in a state of compassion towards the other person.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been meaning to get into the process of taking notes while reading books. Lets start with Nonviolent Communication by Marshall Rosenberg.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id='surface_thoughts'&gt;Surface thoughts&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All communication must be grounded in a state of compassion towards the other person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id='four_tenents_of_nonviolent_communication'&gt;Four tenents of Nonviolent communication&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Observe: I observe the situation or concrete actions.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Feeling: how the above observation makes me feel.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Needs: what needs/values/desires of ours are connected to the feelings we have identified.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Request: the concrete actions we request from the other person in order to enrich our lives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 id='alienating_types_of_communication'&gt;Alienating types of communication&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moralistic judgements (blame, insults, put-downs, labels, criticisms, comparisons) * If my partner wants more affection than I’m giving her, she is “needy and dependent.” But if I want more affection than she is giving me, then she is “aloof and insensitive.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Denial of responsibility. We deny responsibility for our actions when we attribute their cause to&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our condition, diagnosis, personal or psychological history ( I drink because I am an alcoholic).&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The actions of others. This is important in order to not come across as accusatory.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The dictates of authority.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Demands. You can never make a person do anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id='separate_observation_from_evaluation'&gt;Separate observation from evaluation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When we combine observation with evaluation, people are apt to hear criticism.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Keep evaluations at bay: &amp;#8220;John is angry&amp;#8221; is an evaluation, &amp;#8220;John shouted, pounded the table, etc&amp;#8230;&amp;#8221; is an observation. Furthermore, he could in fact be hurt, scared or anxious.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id='identify_and_express_your_own_feelings'&gt;Identify and express your own feelings&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;But also, distinguish between feelings and thoughts. &amp;#8220;I feel inadequate as a guitar player&amp;#8221; is an assessment, instead of &amp;#8220;I feel impatient/disappointed/frustrated as a guitar player&amp;#8221; which are feelings.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Use words that refer to specific emotions, rather than something more general. &amp;#8220;I feel good&amp;#8221; could mean excited, mellow, etc..&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Distinguish between how you feel and how you think others are reacting to behaving towards you. &amp;#8220;I feel misunderstood&amp;#8221; instead actually been anxious or annoyed.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Connect your feelings with your needs. I feel _____ because I ____ : &amp;#8221;I&amp;#8217;m disappointed because I was hoping to see you.&amp;#8221;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Judgements of others are alienated expressions of our own unment needs. Futhermore, expressing our needs we have a better chance of having them met.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id='handling_a_negative_message'&gt;Handling a negative message&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have four option when hearing something negative: &amp;#8220;You&amp;#8217;re really self-centered and a trash-person&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take it personally, and accept others&amp;#8217; judgement.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Blame others. &amp;#8220;Actually, you&amp;#8217;re the one who&amp;#8217;s self centered&amp;#8221;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Sense your own feelings and needs.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Sense others&amp;#8217; feelings and needs (the best choice).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id='listening_empathically'&gt;Listening empathically&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Common responses that prevent empathic listening include advising, one-upping, educating, consoling, story-telling, shutting down, sympathizing, interrogating, explaining and correcting. Intellectual understanding blocks empathy. Simply be wholly present. Listen and attempt to understand what unmet needs people are expressing.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Intro to infosec</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2017/11/09/intro-to-infosec/"/>
    <id>/2017/11/09/intro-to-infosec/</id>
    <published>2017-11-09T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2017-11-09T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;For the past several months I&amp;#8217;ve been pursuing a self-directed education in information security and immersing myself in a wealth of amazing topics. It&amp;#8217;s an incredibly broad field, and daunting in its complexity but then what isn&amp;#8217;t. I figured writing about it would solidify some concepts and organize my thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For the past several months I&amp;#8217;ve been pursuing a self-directed education in information security and immersing myself in a wealth of amazing topics. It&amp;#8217;s an incredibly broad field, and daunting in its complexity but then what isn&amp;#8217;t. I figured writing about it would solidify some concepts and organize my thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My time is currently mostly devoted to reading while I collect tools and provision a sandbox. I settled on this amazing free course from the University of Helsinki for a more structured approach &lt;a href='https://cybersecuritybase.github.io/'&gt;https://cybersecuritybase.github.io/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way I use, write and reason about code has changed significantly. This &lt;a href='https://www.computer.org/cms/CYBSI/docs/Top-10-Flaws.pdf'&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; categorizes software flaws into two groups&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id='implementation_flaws'&gt;Implementation flaws&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The classic bug. This could be an error throw due to an invalid reference, missing resource or just faulty logic. The list is extensive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id='design_flaws'&gt;Design flaws&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where it gets interesting. These flaws are deeper yet all encompassing and include things like error pages leaking information, offloading auth to the client, poor sandboxing and assumption of trust between services or just plain old misconfiguration and leaving things exposed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Design systems assuming they will eventually be compromised, limit trust and live/die by the &lt;a href='https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Principle_of_least_privilege'&gt;principle of least privelege&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#8217;t mix data and control instructions. Allowing untrusted input data to be executed like any other code leads to injection vulnerabilities and control-flow hijacking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Reflections on software development consulting</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2017/10/24/consulting/"/>
    <id>/2017/10/24/consulting/</id>
    <published>2017-10-24T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2017-10-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s been about a year and a half since quitting my job to become self-employed and for the most part it&amp;#8217;s been swell. Having said that, I think it&amp;#8217;s time to cycle back into a team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consulting was great because I got to&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Broaden my non-technical skills. Managing people is a completely different job from building software, but one I enjoyed immensely. What people say and what they actually mean or want are often at conflict, and the ability to help reconcile the two is invaluable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s been about a year and a half since quitting my job to become self-employed and for the most part it&amp;#8217;s been swell. Having said that, I think it&amp;#8217;s time to cycle back into a team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consulting was great because I got to&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Broaden my non-technical skills. Managing people is a completely different job from building software, but one I enjoyed immensely. What people say and what they actually mean or want are often at conflict, and the ability to help reconcile the two is invaluable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make design/architecture/development decisions and manage my own projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Focus on other areas of my life. I am generally smarter, stronger and more well-balanced than ever. Just having the time to think or be bored allowed me to figure out how to lead a more meaningful life, and clarified my goals and priorities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joining a team is becoming a priority because&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My technical skills are stagnating. As the saying goes if you&amp;#8217;re the smartest person in the room you&amp;#8217;re in the wrong room. Working from home alone I am by default the smartest in the room :(&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I need access to a different set of challenges that align with my long-term career trajectory. For the most part clients require the same set of services when it comes to web development: new features or bug fixes. While I got to kick-off some fun green-field projects, much of the work remains of the same nature. Unfortunately this means I haven&amp;#8217;t had exposure to complex systems at scale, or infrastructure and security management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;#8217;t been marketing (nor do I super enjoy it). Luckily all of my work has come through word-of-mouth and referrals, but that&amp;#8217;s drying up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Multi-user git</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2017/10/24/multi-user-git/"/>
    <id>/2017/10/24/multi-user-git/</id>
    <published>2017-10-24T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2017-10-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Modify your ~/.ssh/config file as such to seamlessly utilize multiple git users on the same machine&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Host user1
  Hostname github.com
  User git
  IdentityFile ~/.ssh/username1_pubkey
  IdentitiesOnly yes

Host user2
  Hostname github.com&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Modify your ~/.ssh/config file as such to seamlessly utilize multiple git users on the same machine&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Host user1
  Hostname github.com
  User git
  IdentityFile ~/.ssh/username1_pubkey
  IdentitiesOnly yes

Host user2
  Hostname github.com
  User git
  IdentityFile ~/.ssh/username2_pubkey
  IdentitiesOnly yes&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then for your repo ensure &lt;code&gt;git remote -v&lt;/code&gt; is of the form&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git@user1:&amp;lt;username1&amp;gt;/&amp;lt;username1-repo&amp;gt;.git&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, ensure your ssh key is added to the respective repo.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
